前情提要
你是誰
Who are you?
金·莫裏亞蒂
Jim Moriarty.
你好
Hi!
犯罪顧問
Consulting criminal.
雖然我樂此不疲
I have loved this,
我們之間的小遊戲
this little game of ours.
已經死人了
People have died.
是個人都會死
That's what people do!
我會阻止你
I will stop you.
如果你還繼續追根究底
If you don't stop prying...
我會燒死你
I'll burn you.
會把你架在火上烤熟
I will burn the heart out of you.
回- 頭- 見
Catch you later.
再見才怪
No, you won't!
抱歉  孩子們
Sorry, boys!
我這人就是變化無常
I'm so changeable!
這是我的缺點
It is a weakness with me,
不過平心而論
but to be fair to myself,
這是我僅有的缺點
it is my only weakness.
我不能讓你再窮追不捨
You can't be allowed to continue.
不可以了
You just can't.
我也想過要說服你
I would try to convince you,
不過我要說的你都知道了吧
but everything I have to say has already crossed your mind.
或許我的回答你也同樣清楚
Probably my answer has crossed yours.
"活著"  比吉斯樂隊
"Stayin' Alive" by the Bee Gees
不介意我接個電話吧
Do you mind if I get that?
當然不會  請便
Oh, no, please.
你還有一輩子時間呢
You've got the rest of your life.
喂
Hello?
當然是  你想怎麼樣
Yes, of course it is. What do you want?
再說一遍
Say that again!
再說一遍  記住  如果你騙我
Say that again, and know that if you're lying to me,
我會抓住你  剝皮拆骨
I will find you, and I will skin you.
等著
Wait.
抱歉
Sorry.
死期未到
Wrong day to die.
是嗎
Oh.
你有更好的選擇了嗎
Did you get a better offer?
我們會再見面  夏洛克
You'll be hearing from me, Sherlock.
如果你真有你所說的東西
So if you have what you say you have,
我可以讓你發財
I will make you rich.
如果你沒有
If you don't,
我就用你做人皮皮鞋
I'll make you into shoes.
怎麼回事
What happened there?
有人讓他改變了主意
Someone changed his mind.
問題是...
The question is...
是誰
who?
您可曾試過墮落放縱  殿下
Well, now, have you been wicked, Your Highness?
是的  阿德勒小姐
Yes, Miss Adler.
新福爾摩斯 第2季 第1集
Sherlock S02E01 720p hdtv x264
貝爾格萊維亞醜聞
華生醫生的博客 5月30日
生活在繼續
是時候更新消息了
我打算講述幾個我們最近處理的
小案子
蒂利
·
布裏格斯
歡樂
巡遊
你在寫什麼
What are you typing?
的
真相
一樁
- 博客  - 關於什麼
- Blog.  - About?
關於
我們
Us.
熔化
筆記本
也就是說我
You mean me.
電腦
為什麼
Why?
的
奇怪
案子
因為你打的內容很多
Well, you're typing a lot.
那又怎樣
Right, then.
看看我們有什麼新案子
So, what have we got?
- 我老婆經常工作到很晚 - 無聊
- My wife seems to be spending a very long time at the office.  - Boring.
我想我丈夫可能有外遇
I think my husband might be having an affair.
沒錯
Yes.
她不是我姑姑  她被人調包了
She's not my real aunt, she's been replaced.
我確定這不是她
I know she has.
- 我分辨得出人的骨灰  - 出去
- I know human ash.  - Leave.
無論您提出何種報酬  我們都能滿足
We are prepared to offer any sum of money you care to mention
- 只要能找回這些文件  - 無聊
- for the recovery of these files.  - Boring.
我們建了個網站
We have this website,
用來解釋漫畫書的真正意義
it explains the true meaning of comic books,
因為人們忽略了其中很多主題
cos people miss a lot of the themes.
但隨後所有的漫畫開始變成事實
But then all the comic books started coming true.
有點意思
Oh...interesting.
華生醫生的博客
極客漫畫通
三個年輕人來到
貝克街
聲稱
極客漫畫通  那是什麼
Geek Interpreter, what's that?
是標題
That's the title.
標題有啥用
What does it need a title for?
漫畫
故事
真有人讀你的博客嗎
Do people actually read your blog?
那你以為那些委託人是怎麼找來的
Where do you think our clients come from?
我自己有網站
I have a website.
你在上面列舉了240種不同的煙灰
In which you enumerate 240 different types of tobacco ash.
沒人看你的網站
Nobody's reading your website.
這就對了  漂染金髮  沒有明顯死因
Right then, dyed blonde hair, no obvious cause of death,
除了這些不知是啥的斑點
except for these speckles, whatever they are.
真的假的
Oh, for God's sakes!
- 幹嘛  - 斑點金髮女
- What?  - The Speckled Blonde?!
華生醫生的博客
斑點金髮女
三十來歲  漂染金髮
身上覆滿奇怪紅斑
爺爺去世時他們不讓我們去看他
They wouldn't let us see Granddad when he was dead.
是因為他去了天堂嗎
Is that cos he'd gone to heaven?
人死了不會去天堂
People don't really go to heaven when they die,
他們被送到特定地點燒掉
they're taken to a special room and burned.
夏洛克
Sherlock...
昨天杜塞爾多夫[德]發生一起空難
There was a plane crash in Dusseldorf yesterday.
全員遇難
Everyone dead.
疑似遭恐怖分子炸毀
Suspected terrorist bomb.
我們也看新聞
We do watch the news.
你說著無聊就換台了
You said "Boring" and turned over.
從航班記錄上發現
Well, according to the flight details,
此人已辦理登機手續
this man was checked in on board.
他的大衣裏有登機牌的存根
Inside his coat he's got a stub from his boarding pass,
航班上的餐巾紙
napkins from the flight,
還有航班特供餅乾
even one of those special biscuits.
這是他的護照  在柏林機場蓋過戳
Here's his passport, stamped at Berlin Airport.
所以這人昨天本該死在德國的空難中
So this man should have died in a plane crash in Germany yesterday,
結果卻死在薩瑟克區的汽車後備箱裏
but instead he's in a car boot in Southwark.
是禍躲不過
Lucky escape.
有想法嗎
Any ideas?
目前有八個
Eight so far.
好吧  是四個
OK, four ideas.
也許只有兩個
Maybe two ideas.
華生醫生的博客
夏洛克·福爾摩斯的困惑
薩裏郡荒地汽車內發現45歲男子屍體
不  不要提未解決的案子
No, no, no, don't mention the unsolved ones.
華生醫生的博客
夏洛克·福爾摩斯的困惑
薩裏郡荒地汽車內發現45歲男子屍體
人們想看到你凡人的一面
People want to know you're human.
為啥
Why?
因為他們感興趣
Because they're interested.
才怪  他們為啥感興趣
No, they're not. Why are they?
看看這個
Hmm, look at that.
- 1895  - 你說什麼
- 1,895.  - Sorry, what?
我昨晚重置了訪客計數
I reset that counter last night.
在過去八小時裏
This blog has had nearly 2,000 hits
有將近2000人點擊博客
in the last eight hours.
這就是你的生計來源  夏洛克
This is your living, Sherlock,
才不是什麼240種煙灰
not 240 different types of tobacco ash.
是243種
243.
這次用什麼標題
So what's this one?
肚臍謀殺案
Belly Button Murders?
肚臍療法
The Navel Treatment?
外面有很多記者  夥計們
There's a lot of press outside, guys.
反正不是衝著我們來
Well, they won't be interested in us.
那是在你走紅網絡前
Yeah, that was before you were an internet phenomenon.
其中一些人特別要求拍你們的照片
A couple of them specifically wanted photographs of you two.
老天
God's sake!
約翰
John.
遮住臉  快走
Cover your face and walk fast.
這有助於營造良好公眾形象
Still, it's good for the public image,
畢竟是這樣的大案子
big case like this.
我是私家偵探  公眾形象毫無益處
I'm a private detective, the last thing I need is a public image.
帽子俠和羅賓:網絡偵探二人組
夏洛克和網絡技術
夏洛克和約翰  博客控偵探
夏洛克·福爾摩斯  網絡奇人
喂
Hello.
我想是時候了  你說呢
I think it's time, don't you?
天啊
Oh, dear!
手指
Thumbs!?
大門...
The door was...
小伙子們  有新客戶了
Boys! You've got another one!
從頭說  別讓我覺得無聊
Tell us from the start, don't be boring.
14小時前
喂
Hey!
你還好嗎
Are you OK?
你好
Excuse me!
你沒事吧
Are you all right?
長官  您的電話
Sir, phone call for you.
我是卡特
Carter.
- 聽說過夏洛克·福爾摩斯嗎  - 誰
- Have you heard of Sherlock Holmes?  - Who?
你很快就會見到他
Well, you're about to meet him now.
這是你的案子  你說了算  我只是
This is your case, it's entirely up to you, this is just...
給你提個友好建議
friendly advice, but
讓夏洛克在犯罪現場調查五分鐘
give Sherlock five minutes on your crime scene,
他怎麼說你都聽著
and listen to everything that he has to say.
還有盡量...
And as far as possible...
不要揍他
try not to punch him.
好的
Ok.
長官  這位先生說
Sir, this gentleman says
- 他要跟您談談  - 我知道
- he needs to speak to you...  - Yes, I know.
夏洛克·福爾摩斯
Sherlock Holmes.
約翰·華生  這裏能無線上網嗎
John Watson. Are you set up for Wi- Fi?
你也知道這有點丟人吧
You realise this is a tiny bit humiliating?
還好  無所謂
It's OK, I'm fine.
現在
Now...
讓我看看河邊
show me to the stream.
我不是說丟你的人
I didn't really mean for you.
聽著  這才第六起
Look, this is a six.
第七起之前我離開公寓去勘察毫無意義
There's no point in my leaving the flat for anything
我們已經達成共識了
less than a seven, we agreed.
現在往後退
Now go back,
讓我看草地
show me the grass.
我們什麼時候達成的共識
When did we agree that?
昨天  停
We agreed it yesterday. Stop!
- 近點  - 我昨天根本不在家
- Closer.  - I wasn't even at home yesterday.
我去了都柏林
I was in Dublin.
你沒聽見是你的問題
It's hardly my fault you weren't listening.
- 閉嘴  - 我不在家你還一個人叨叨
- Shut up!  - Do you just carry on talking when I'm away?
誰知道你什麼時候不在家
I don't know, how often are you away?
現在
Now...
讓我看看排氣管回火那車
show me the car that backfired.
在那邊
It's there.
就是這輛車發出巨響的吧
That's the one that made the noise, yes?
對
Yeah.
如果你在考慮槍擊...
If you're thinking gunshot...
沒有槍擊
There wasn't one.
他沒有中彈
He wasn't shot,
致命傷是
he was killed by a single
背後一處鈍器重擊
blow to the back from a blunt instrument,
但兇器和兇手一起神秘消失了
which then magically disappeared, along with the killer.
我看這次至少得有八起案子
It's got to be an eight, at least.
你還有兩分鐘
You've got two more minutes,
他們想知道更多司機的信息
they want to know more about the driver.
不用管他  他是個白癡
Oh, forget him, he's an idiot.
他怎麼會認為自己是疑犯
Why else would he think himself a suspect?
是我認為他有嫌疑
I think he's a suspect.
- 把電腦遞過去  - 好吧
- Pass me over.  - All right,
要是有靜音按鈕  我巴不得馬上按掉
but there's a mute button, and I will use it.
舉高點  我才不要在下面說話
Up a bit! I'm not talking from down here!
好吧  你舉著  舉著吧
OK. Just take it, take it.
成功謀殺且沒有證人
Having successfully committed a crime without a single witness...
他何必又叫警察又找偵探
why would he call the police and consult a detective?
- 想跟你公平競賽  - 他在耍小聰明
- Fair play?  - He's trying to be clever.
他是過於自負了
It's overconfidence.
你見過他嗎
Did you see him?
過度肥胖
Morbidly obese,
口臭熏天證明是單身漢
the undisguised halitosis of a single man living on his own.
右袖子證明他沉迷於色情網站
The right sleeve of an internet porn addict,
呼吸模式證明他是未治療的心臟病患者
the breathing pattern of an untreated heart condition.
自尊低  智商低  命不長久
Low self- esteem, tiny IQ and a limited life expectancy,
你居然認為他能策劃罪案
and you think he's a criminal mastermind?!
別擔心  這推論傻瘋了
Don't worry, this is just stupid.
你說什麼  我心臟怎麼了
What did you say? Heart what?
去河邊
Go to the stream.
河裏有什麼
What's in the stream?
- 過去看看  - 夏洛克
- Go and see.  - Sherlock!
你怎麼不應門
You weren't answering your doorbell.
他的臥室在後面  去拿些衣服
His room's through the back, get him some clothes.
你們到底是什麼人
Who the hell are you?
抱歉  福爾摩斯先生...
Sorry, Mr Holmes...
- 夏洛克  怎麼了  - 您得跟我們走
- Sherlock, what's going on? What's happening?  - You're coming with us.
信號斷了  不知怎麼...
I've lost him. I don't know what...
- 華生醫生  - 我是
- Dr Watson?  - Yeah.
- 找您的  - 好  謝謝
- It's for you.  - OK, thanks.
不  先生  是直升機
No, sir, the helicopter.
福爾摩斯先生  您要去的那個地方
Please, Mr Holmes, where you're going
您一定會希望著裝得體
you'll want to be dressed.
西裝：
700鎊
無武器
修剪
整齊
坐辦公室
慣用右手
室內工作
小狗
x2
x3
我很清楚我要去哪兒
I know exactly where I'm going.
- 你穿了褲子嗎  - 沒有  - 好吧
- You wearing any pants? - No. - OK.
我們在白金漢宮哎  很好
At Buckingham Palace. Right.
我在努力克制偷煙灰缸的衝動
Aah, aah, I am seriously fighting an impulse to steal an ashtray.
我們來這裏做什麼
What are we doing here,
- 夏洛克  正經回答我  - 我不知道
- Sherlock, seriously, what? - I don't know.
是來謁見女王嗎
Here to see the Queen?
很顯然  你說對了
Oh, apparently, yes.
拜託你們一回  別這麼幼稚好嗎
Just once, can you two behave like grown- ups?
我們破案  我用博客記錄  他忘了穿褲子
We solve crimes, I blog about it, and he forgets his pants.
我對此不抱太大希望
I wouldn't hold out too much hope.
麥考夫  我手頭還有案子
I was in the middle of a case, mycroft.
什麼案子  驢友和發動機回火事件
What, the hiker and the backfire?
我過了一眼警方報告  有點平淡無奇了吧
I glanced at the police report, a bit obvious, surely?
- 顯而易見  - 那就別操心了
- Transparent. - Time to move on then.
這裏是白金漢宮
We are in Buckingham Palace,
整個英國的中樞之地
the very heart of the British nation.
- 夏洛克·福爾摩斯  穿上褲子  - 為啥
- Sherlock Holmes, put your trousers on! - What for?
為了客戶
Your client.
我的這位客戶...
And my client is...?
地位顯赫  尊榮至極
Illustrious, in the extreme.
所以我必須說明  客戶的名字保密
And remaining, I have to inform you, entirely anonymous.
- 麥考夫  - 哈瑞
- Mycroft. - Harry.
舍弟禮數不周  請允許我
May I just apologise for the state
- 代他道歉  - 我想是他太忙了吧
- of my little brother. - A full- time occupation, I imagine.
這位一定是約翰·華生醫生
And this must be Dr John Watson,
曾在第五諾森伯蘭兵團服役
formerly of the Fifth Northumberland Fusiliers?
正是  你好
Hello, yes.
- 我老闆非常喜歡你的博客  - 你老闆
- My employer is a tremendous fan of your blog. - Your employer?
尤其喜歡寫鋁枴杖的那一篇
Particularly enjoyed the one about the aluminium crutch.
謝謝
Thank you.
這位年輕的福爾摩斯先生
And Mr Holmes the Younger.
你沒有照片上那麼高
You look taller in your photographs.
多虧那件修身外套和這位矮個子朋友
I take the precaution of a good coat and a short friend.
麥考夫  我不接匿名客戶
Mycroft, I don't do anonymous clients.
我習慣了案子一頭是謎
I'm used to mystery at one end of my cases,
兩頭都是謎就太麻煩了  再見
both ends is too much work. Good morning.
此案事關國家  別鬧了
This is a matter of national importance. Grow up!
- 鬆開我的床單  - 不然呢
- Get off my sheet! - Or what?
不然我就直接走出去
Or I'll just walk away.
- 那我成全你  - 兩位  注意場合
- I'll let you. - Boys, please...not here.
這位客戶到底是誰
Who is my client?
看看你在什麼地方  然後動腦筋想想
Take a look at where you're standing, and make a deduction.
雇你的是全國最有權勢的人  還要點明嗎
You are to be engaged by the highest in the land, now, for God's sake!
快把衣服穿上
Put your clothes on!
我負責招呼
I'll be mother.
我從小到大就是聽你招呼
And there is a whole childhood in a nutshell.
我老闆遇到了棘手的問題
My employer has a problem.
這件事極其敏感  存在犯罪的可能性
A matter has come to light of an extremely delicate
如今面臨曝光的危險
and potentially criminal nature,
在此緊急關頭
and in this hour of need,
- 親愛的弟弟  有人想到了你  - 為什麼
- dear brother, your name has arisen. - Why?
我們有各種各樣的警力
We have a police force of sorts,
還有無孔不入的軍情六處
even a marginally secret service.
- 為什麼來找我  - 大家都找你幫忙
- Why come to me? - People come to you for help,
對吧  福爾摩斯先生
don't they, Mr Holmes?
但名下有海軍的人可沒找過我
Not to date anyone with a navy.
此案關係到最高機密  以及信任問題
This is a matter of the highest security, and therefore of trust.
- 連自家的情報機關也信不過  - 當然
- You don't trust your own secret service? - Naturally not.
他們都為了錢監視別人
They all spy on people for money.
我們時間有限
I do think we have a timetable.
是的  當然了
Yes, of course. Erm...
你認識這個女人嗎
What do you know about this woman?
沒印象
Nothing whatsoever.
那你就要多加注意了
Then you should be paying more attention.
她去年成為兩起政黨醜聞的焦點
She's been at the centre of two political scandals in the last year,
最近又與某著名作家離婚
and recently ended the marriage of a prominent novelist
我送你一份禮物
因為她不僅給老公帶綠帽子  還腳踏兩條船
by having an affair with both participants separately.
你知道我對花邊新聞不感興趣
You know I don't concern myself with trivia.
她是誰
Who is she?
艾琳·阿德勒
Irene Adler.
業內稱她為"那個女人"
Professionally known as "The Woman".
業內
Professionally?
她有很多外號  她最喜歡"施虐女王"
There are many names for what she does. She prefers "Dominatrix".
讀取圖片>>
- 施虐女王  - 別緊張
- Dominatrix. - Don't be alarmed.
是性方面的
It's to do with sex.
性不會讓我緊張
Sex doesn't alarm me.
你怎麼知道
How would you know?
她提供的是  這樣說吧  愉悅的懲罰
She provides, shall we say, recreational scolding
給那些有此嗜好
for those who enjoy that sort of thing
且樂意付錢的人
and are prepared to pay for it.
這些是從她的網站下載的
These are all from her website.
我猜這位阿德勒女士有一些不能見光的照片
And I assume this Adler woman has some compromising photographs.
你反應很快  福爾摩斯先生
You're very quick, Mr Holmes.
不難推斷  到底是誰的照片
Hardly a difficult deduction. Photographs of whom?
一個對我老闆很重要的人
A person of significance to my employer.
希望我們不要再談這方面的事了
We'd prefer not to say any more at this time.
你們什麼都不說嗎
You can't tell us anything?
我可以告訴你們  是個年輕人
I can tell you it's a young person.
一位年輕女性
A young female person.
照片有多少張
How many photographs?
很顯然  數量非常大
A considerable number, apparently.
阿德勒小姐和這位年輕女性
Do Miss Adler and this young female
- 同時出現在照片裏  - 是的
- person appear in these photographs together? - Yes.
我猜照片上有許多不能見光的場景
I assume in a number of compromising scenarios?
照我們的想像  這是肯定的
An imaginative range, we are assured.
約翰  你現在最好把茶杯放下
John, you might want to put that cup back in your saucer now.
- 你能幫忙嗎  福爾摩斯先生  - 怎麼幫
- Can you help us, Mr Holmes? - How?
願意接這個案子嗎
Will you take the case?
什麼案子
What case?
立刻給錢  要多少給多少
Pay her, now and in full.
等阿德勒小姐公佈照片
As Miss Adler remarks in her masthead,
你們就能領教她的厲害了
know when you are beaten.
她什麼都不要
She doesn't want anything.
她聯繫過我們
She got in touch.
她通知我們說她有那些照片
She informed us that the photographs existed.
明確表示沒打算使用這些照片
She indicated that she had no intention to use them
敲詐錢財或是別的什麼
to extort either money or favour.
炫耀力量
Oh, a power play.
向大英最有權勢的家族炫耀力量
A power play with the most powerful family in Britain.
不愧是施虐女王
Now that is a dominatrix.
這就很有趣了嘛  對吧
Ooh, this is getting rather fun, isn't it.
- 夏洛克  - 她在哪裏
- Sherlock... - Hmm. Where is she?
她目前在倫敦  她在...
In London, currently. She's staying...
細節問題發短信給我  晚上再跟你們聯繫
Text me the details, I'll be in touch by the end of the day.
你確定到時候能搞到消息嗎
Do you really think you'll have news by then?
不  我到時候能搞到照片
No, I think I'll have the photographs.
但願你真像說的那麼神奇
One can only hope you're as good as you seem to think.
愛狗
騎馬
公立學校
早起
睡左邊
不抽煙
父親
一半威爾士血統
書迷
嗜茶
當然了  我還需要一樣東西
I'll need some equipment, of course.
要什麼都行  我會派人送到...
Anything you require, I'll have it sent...
- 能給我一盒火柴嗎  - 你說什麼
- Can I have a box of matches? - I'm sorry?
或者是打火機  都可以
Or your cigarette lighter, either will do.
- 我不抽煙  - 這我知道  但你老闆抽煙
- I don't smoke. - No, I know you don't, but your employer does.
這件小事我們一直對外隱瞞著
We have kept a lot of people successfully in the dark
大多數人都不知道  福爾摩斯先生
about this little fact, Mr Holmes.
我不是大多數
I'm not the Commonwealth.
他這樣算是謙虛了
And that's as modest as he gets.
很高興見到你
Pleasure to meet you.
回見
Laters!
好吧  你怎麼知道抽煙的事
OK, the smoking, how did you know?
證據就在你眼皮底下  約翰
The evidence was right under your nose, John,
你看見了  卻沒有注意到
as ever you see, but do not observe.
- 注意到什麼  - 煙灰缸
- Observe what? - The ashtray.
凱特
Kate?
有客人來了
We're going to have a visitor.
我要花點時間準備一下
I'll need a bit of time to get ready.
要很久嗎
A long time?
很久很久
Hmm...ages.
你幹什麼呢
What are you doing?
我要上戰場了  約翰
I'm going to into battle, John.
得換一身好盔甲
I need the right armour.
不好
No.
Nah.
我看很好
Works for me.
你看什麼都好
Everything works on you.
計劃是什麼
So, what's the plan?
我們知道她的地址
We know her address.
直接按她家門鈴嗎
We just ring her doorbell?
沒錯  就在這兒停
Exactly. Just here, please.
你根本就沒有換衣服
You didn't even change your clothes.
所以該添點兒顏色了
Then it's time to add a splash of colour.
到了嗎
Are we here?
還有兩條街  但就在這兒做吧
Two streets away, but this will do.
- 做什麼  - 朝我的臉來一拳
- For what? - Punch me in the face.
什麼顏色
Shade?
血紅
Blood.
- 打你  - 沒錯  打我的臉  沒聽見嗎
- Punch you? - Yes, punch me, in the face. Didn't you hear me?
經常聽你說"揍我"  不過一般都是潛台詞
I always hear "Punch me" when you speak but it's usually sub- text.
真是婆婆媽媽
Oh, for God's sakes!
謝了  這樣就...
Thank you, that was...
行了  我們打完了  約翰
OK, I think we're done now, John!
你記清楚  夏洛克  我當過兵  殺過人
You want to remember, Sherlock, I was a soldier. I killed people.
- 你是軍醫  - 我也有心情不好的時候
- You were a doctor! - I had bad days!
你打算穿什麼
What are you going to wear?
- 招牌戰衣  - 幸運的傢伙
- My battle dress. - Oh, lucky boy.
你好
Hello?
很抱歉打攪你
Oh, very sorry to disturb you,
剛才有人打了我
um, I've just been attacked, um,
他們好像拿走了我的錢包
um, and I think they, they took my wallet
還有手機
and, um, and my phone.
你能幫幫我嗎
Um, please could you help me?
需要的話  我可以幫你報警
I can phone the police, if you want?
謝謝  請幫我報警
Thank you. Could you, please?
我就在這兒等他們來  你不介意吧
Would you mind if I just waited here, just until they come?
謝謝你  萬分感謝
Thank you, thank you so much.
謝謝
Thank you. Oh.
我當時在場
I saw it all happen.
沒關係  我是醫生
It's OK, I'm a doctor.
- 你有急救箱嗎  - 在廚房裏  請便
- Have you got a first aid kit? - In the kitchen. Please.
- 謝謝  - 謝謝
- Thank you. - Thank you.
好可憐  聽說你受傷了
Hello, sorry to hear you've been hurt.
- 凱特還沒問過你的名字吧  - 抱歉  我
- I don't think Kate caught your name? - I'm so sorry, I'm...
人在大吃一驚的時候
It's always hard to remember an alias
很難想起編好的化名  對吧
when you've had a fright. Isn't it?
瞧啊
Well, there now.
我們都暴露了
We're both defrocked...
夏洛克·福爾摩斯先生
..Mr Sherlock Holmes.
- 你是艾琳·阿德勒吧  - 瞧瞧這對顴骨
- Miss Adler, I presume. - Look at those cheekbones.
要是一巴掌扇過去我會割到手
I could cut myself slapping that face.
要不要我來試試
Would you like me to try?
好了  這就行了
Right, this should do it.
看來我錯過了一場好戲
I've missed something, haven't I?
請坐  想喝茶的話  我叫女僕送來
Please, sit down. Or if you'd like some tea, I can call the maid.
我在宮裏喝過了
I had some at the Palace.
- 我知道  - 很顯然
- I know. - Clearly.
我也在宮裏喝過茶了  如果有人要問的話
I had a tea too, at the Palace. If anyone's interested.
兩天沒換的襯衫
手動剃鬚
今晚有約會
沒給姐姐打電話
新牙刷
夜不歸宿
和史丹佛
一起
你知道偽裝的最大問題嗎  福爾摩斯先生
Do you know the big problem with a disguise, Mr Holmes?
無論你多麼努力  總是一幅自畫像
However hard you try, it's always a self- portrait.
你覺得我是頭破血流的牧師
You think I'm a vicar with a bleeding face?
不  我覺得你神志不清
No, I think you're damaged,
沉溺幻想  堅持無上的權威
delusional and believe in a higher power.
而你的權威  便是你自己
In your case, it's yourself.
有人很愛惜你嘛
Hmm, and somebody loves you.
如果要我打你的臉  我也會避開鼻子和牙齒
If I had to punch that face, I'd avoid your nose and teeth, too.
哈哈  你能別這樣光著身子嗎
Ha- ha! Could you put something on, please?
- 拿紙巾遮一遮吧  - 怎麼  你很尷尬
- Er, anything at all. A napkin? - Why? Are you feeling exposed?
我認為約翰並不知道該看哪
I don't think John knows where to look.
不會  他很清楚該看哪
No, I think he knows exactly where.
倒是你  我不敢肯定
I'm not sure about you.
我要是想看女人的裸體  就借約翰的手提
If I was to look at naked women, I'd borrow John's laptop.
- 你確實借了我的手提  - 那是沒收
- You do borrow my laptop. - I confiscate it.
算了  我們還有正經事要談
Never mind, we've got better things to talk about.
現在  坦白告訴我
Now, tell me, I need to know -
案子的經過如何
how was it done?
什麼案子
What?
腦袋挨了一下的驢友  他怎麼死的
The hiker with the bashed- in head - how was he killed?
我來不是為了這件事
That's not why I'm here.
當然不是  你的目標是拿走照片
No, no, no. You're here for the photographs,
但我不會讓你拿到  所以不如我們隨便聊聊
but that's never going to happen and as we're chatting...anyway
那個案子沒有公開  你怎麼知道
That story's not out. How do you know about it?
我認識一位警察  我知道他的癖好
I know one of the policemen. Well, I know what he likes.
你喜歡警察
And you...like policemen?
我喜歡偵探故事  還有偵探
I like detective stories. And detectives.
腦袋好使的人很性感
Brainy is the new sexy.
車位置
The position car...
車的位置與驢友有關係
The position of the car relative to the hiker,
還有那致命一擊
that and the fact that the death blow
來自他的腦後  你知道這些就夠了
was to the back of the head, that's all you need to know.
- 好吧  告訴我他怎麼被殺  - 不是被殺
- OK, tell me, how was he murdered? - He wasn't.
你覺得不是兇殺嗎
You don't think it was murder?
- 我知道不是  - 怎麼知道
- I know it wasn't. - How?
就像我知道死者是位出色的冒險家
The same way that I know the victim was a excellent sportsman,
剛從海外旅行歸來
recently returned from foreign travel
而我要找的照片就在這個房間裏
and that the photographs I'm looking for are in this room.
- 好吧  可怎麼知道  - 這麼說還真在  謝謝
- OK, but how? - So they are in this room. Thank you.
約翰  把守房門  別讓人進來
John, man the door, let no- one in.
鄉村野外  只有兩個男人
Two men alone in the countryside,
相隔幾碼遠  還有一輛車
several yards apart and one car.
我以為你要開始找照片了
Oh, I... I thought you were looking for the photos now.
不  不
No, no.
找要花上好久  我能直接找到
Looking takes ages, I'm just going to find them,
不過你還算聰明  我們又有時間
but you're moderate clever and we've got a moment,
所以我們消遣一下吧
so let's pass the time.
兩個人  一輛車  沒有其他人了
Two men, a car, nobody else.
司機想要修好他的發動機
Driver's trying to fix his engine.
毫無進展
Getting nowhere.
而驢友正在休息  望著天空
And the hiker is taking a moment, looking at the sky.
是在看鳥嗎
Watching the birds?
隨時都會有事要發生  什麼事
Any moment now, something is going to happen. What?
- 驢友要死了  - 不對
- The hiker is going to die. - No,
那是結果  要發生什麼事
that's the result. What's going to happen?
- 我不懂  - 試著去理解吧
- I don't understand. - Oh, well try to.
- 為什麼  - 因為你迎合衰人的幻想
- Why? - Because you cater to the whims of the pathetic
脫得精光只為了讓人印象深刻
and take your clothes off to make an impression.
別讓我無聊  開動腦筋吧  這是時下流行的性感
Stop boring me and think. It's the new sexy.
車要回火了
The car's going to backfire.
會發出很大的響聲
There's going to be a loud noise.
- 那又如何  - 聲音很重要
- So what? - Oh. Noises are important.
聲音會告訴你一切  比如...
Noises can tell you everything. For instance...
謝謝
Thank you.
聽到火警警報  母親會向孩子的方向望去
On hearing a smoke alarm, a mother would look towards her child.
大火能暴露我們最在意的東西  真神奇
Amazing how fire exposes our priorities.
我真心希望這裏面沒有小孩子
I really hope you don't have a baby in here.
好了  約翰  你可以把警報關掉了
All right, John, you can turn it off now.
我說你可以關掉了
I said you can turn it off now!
稍等
Give me a minute!
多謝
Thank you.
按鍵的時候要記得戴手套
You should always use gloves with these things, you know.
最先按到的鍵上的油漬總是最重
Heaviest oil deposit is always on the first key used,
顯然就是3了
that's quite clear the 3,
但這之後的按鍵順序幾乎看不出來
but after that, the sequence is almost impossible to read.
這樣的保險箱應該是六位密碼
I see it's a six digit code.
不可能是你的生日  無意冒犯
Can't be your birthday, no disrespect,
但你顯然是個八零後  而8幾乎沒用到
but clearly you were born in the '80s and 8's barely used, so...
我現在就能告訴你密碼
I'd tell you the code right now,
但其實呢  我已經告訴你了
but you know what? I already have.
開動腦筋吧
Think.
手放在腦後  跪在地上  別動
Hands behind your head, on the floor, keep it still!
抱歉  夏洛克
Sorry, Sherlock.
阿德勒小姐  跪在地上
Miss Adler, on the floor!
你不要我也跪在地上嗎
Don't you want me on the floor,too?
不  先生  我要你打開保險箱
No, sir, I want you to open the safe.
美國人  有意思  你們怎麼會感興趣
American. Interesting. Why would you care?
- 先生  立刻打開保險箱  - 我不知道密碼
- Sir, the safe, now, please. - I don't know the code.
我們一直在監聽  她說她告訴你了
We've been listening, she said she told you.
如果你們真的在聽  就會知道她沒說
Well, if you've been listening, you'll know she didn't.
我想我一定漏了什麼
I'm assuming I missed something.
而你這麼聰明的人肯定沒有漏掉  福爾摩斯先生
From your reputation, I'm assuming you didn't, Mr Holmes.
老天爺  她才是知道密碼的人  問她
For God's sake, she's the one who knows the code, ask her!
確實  先生  不過她也知道
Yes, sir, she also knows the code
能自動報警  觸響被盜警報的密碼
that automatically calls the police and sets off the burglar alarm.
我已經學會不去信任這個女人了
I've learned not to trust this woman.
- 福爾摩斯先生不...  - 閉嘴
- Mr Holmes doesn't... - Shut up!
你再說一個字  一個字
One more word out of you, just one
我就崩得你腦漿塗牆
and I will decorate that wall with the insides of your head.
這對我來說可不是難事
That, for me, will not be a hardship.
- 亞徹先生  數到三  殺了華生醫生  - 什麼
- Mr Archer, at the count of three, shoot Dr Watson. - What?
我不知道密碼
I don't know the code.
- 一  - 我不知道密碼
- One.- I don't know the code.
- 二  - 她沒告訴我  我不知道
- Two.- She didn't tell me, I don't know it!
我隨時都準備相信你了
I'm prepared to believe you, any second now.
- 三  - 別  住手
- Three! - No, stop!
謝謝你  福爾摩斯先生  請打開
Thank you, Mr Holmes. Open it, please.
好戲上演
Vatican cameos!
- 有勞了  - 好的
- Do you mind? - Not at all.
他死了
He's dead.
謝謝
Thank you.
- 你觀察力十分敏銳  - 觀察力
- You were very observant. - Observant?
- 我受寵若驚  - 不必
- I'm flattered. - Don't be.
- 受寵若驚  - 他們還會有人趕來
- Flattered? - There'll be more of them,
他們肯定有人盯著這棟樓
they'll be keeping an eye on the building.
- 我們該報警  - 對
- We should call the police. - Yes.
- 這就來  - 天吶
- On their way. - For God's sake!
閉嘴  這樣快
Oh, shut up, it's quick.
檢查房子其他房間  看看他們怎麼進來的
Check the rest of the house, see how they got in.
這就是囊中的珍寶了
Well, that's the knighthood in the bag.
那是我的東西
Oh, and that's mine.
手機已鎖
請輸入密碼
我想照片都在這裏了吧
All the photographs are on here, I presume?
- 我當然還有副本  - 你沒有
- I have copies, of course. - No, you don't.
你肯定徹底解除了任何數據傳輸功能
You'll have permanently disabled any kind of uplink or connection.
如果不能證明這部電話裏的內容獨一無二
Unless the contents of this phone prove to be unique,
你也賣不出去
you wouldn't be able to sell them.
誰說我要賣了
Who said I'm selling?
要不他們怎麼會感興趣
Well, why would they be interested?
不管手機裏有什麼  顯然不止是照片那麼簡單
Whatever's on the phone, it's clearly not just photographs.
那部攝像手機是我的身家性命  福爾摩斯先生
That camera- phone is my life, Mr Holmes.
要我給你除非我死了  它是我的護盾
I'd die before I let you take it. It's my protection.
- 夏洛克  - 現在不是了
- Sherlock! - It was.
- 一定是從這邊進來的  - 顯然
- Must have come in this way. - Clearly.
沒事  她只是昏過去了而已
It's all right, she's just out cold.
天曉得她都習慣了
Oh, God knows she's used to that.
還有個後門  快去檢查一下吧  華生醫生
There's a back door. Better check it, Dr Watson.
好吧
Sure.
你很冷靜
You're very calm.
你的陷阱剛剛殺了個人
Well, your booby trap did just kill a man.
不然他也會殺我
He would have killed me.
那是搶先自衛
It was self defence in advance.
那是什麼  是什麼
What is that?! What?
給我
Give it to me.
快給我
Now. Give it to me.
不
No.
- 給我  - 不要
- Give it to me. - Argh! No.
天吶
Oh, for goodness sake!
放手
Drop it.
我...說...放手
I...said...drop it!
謝了  親愛的
Ah, thank you, dear.
好了  去轉告那個時髦的小可愛
Now, tell that sweet little posh thing
照片放在我這兒很安全
the pictures are safe with me.
我不會用它們勒索她  只是為了保險
They're not for blackmail, just for insurance.
再說  我可能還想再見見她呢
Besides, I might want to see her again.
不不不  別這樣
Oh, no no no no no no no.
很榮幸跟你交手
It's been a pleasure.
別掃興
Don't spoil it.
我就想你這樣記住我
This is how I want you to remember me,
記住我是打敗了你的女人
the woman who beat you.
晚安  夏洛克·福爾摩斯先生
Goodnight, Mr Sherlock Holmes.
- 天吶  你做了什麼  - 他會睡上幾個小時
- Jesus! What are you doing? - He'll sleep for a few hours.
別讓他被自己的嘔吐物嗆死了
Make sure he doesn't choke on his own vomit,
要不屍體會很難看
it makes for a very unattractive corpse.
這是怎麼了  你給他下了什麼  夏洛克
What's this? What have you given him? Sherlock?
他會沒事的
He'll be fine.
我在很多朋友身上都用過
I've used it on loads of my friends.
夏洛克  能聽見我說話嗎
Sherlock, can you hear me?
要知道  我想錯了他
You know, I was wrong about him.
他確實知道該往哪看
He did know where to look.
看什麼  你在說什麼
For what? What are you talking about?
我保險箱的密碼
The key- code to my safe.
是什麼
What was it?
我該告訴他嗎
Shall I tell him?
是我的三圍
My measurements.
懂了
Got it!
別說話  別起來  我來說
Oh, ssh ssh no, don't get up, I'll do the talking.
車就要回火了  而驢友
So, the car's about to backfire and the hiker,
他正盯著天空看
he's staring at the sky.
你說他可能是在看鳥  但並非如此  是不是
Now, you said he could be watching birds, but he wasn't, was he?
他是在看另一種飛行物
He was watching another kind of flying thing.
汽車回火  驢友回過頭去看
The car backfires and the hiker turns to look...
而這正是他犯的大錯
..Which was his big mistake.
等司機抬頭看的時候
By the time the driver looks up,
驢友已經死了  他沒看到殺死他的東西
the hiker is already dead. What he doesn't see is what killed him
因為那東西已經被水沖到下游了
because it's already being washed downstream.
一位經驗豐富的冒險家
An accomplished sportsman
剛從海外旅行歸來  還帶了個...
recently returned from foreign travel with...
飛去來器回來
a boomerang.
你看一眼就明白了
You got that from one look?
絕對是時下流行的性感
Definitely the new sexy.
我...
I...
別說話了
Hush, now.
沒事的
It's OK.
我只是來還你的大衣
I'm only returning your coat.
約翰
John?
John!
- 你沒事吧  - 我怎麼回來的
- You OK? - How did I get here?
我想你大概記不得了
I don't suppose you remember much,
你一直在胡言亂語
you weren't making a lot of sense.
我該提醒你一聲
Oh, I should warn you,
我想雷斯垂德用手機把你拍下來了
I think Lestrade filmed you on his phone.
- 她在哪  - 誰在哪
- Where is she? - Where's who?
- 那個女人  就是那個女人  - 什麼女人
- The woman, that woman. - What woman?
- 那個女人  就是那一位  - 艾琳·阿德勒嗎
- The Woman! The Woman, woman! - Oh, Irene Adler?
她跑了  沒人看見她
She got away, no- one saw her.
她不在這兒  夏洛克
She wasn't here, Sherlock.
你在幹什麼  別別別  回到床上去
What are you? What? No, no, no. No. Back to bed.
你早上就會沒事了  睡吧
You'll be fine in the morning. Just sleep.
我當然會沒事  我就是沒事  絕對沒事
Of course I'll be fine, I am fine. I'm absolutely fine.
是啊  你好得不得了
Yes, you're great.
你需要我的話  我就在隔壁
Now, I'll be next door if you need me.
- 我為什麼會需要你  - 不為什麼
- Why would I need you? - No reason at all.
下次再見
福爾摩斯先生
照片很安全
The photographs are perfectly safe.
在一個在逃的性工作者手上叫安全
In the hands of a fugitive sex worker?
她並不想勒索誰
She's not interested in blackmail.
她只想...得到保護  不知是為何
She wants...protection, for some reason.
我想你應該退出警方
I take it you've stood down the police investigation
對她家槍擊案的調查了吧
into the shooting at her house?
她手裏有照片
How can we do anything while
我們又能做什麼  我們無能為力
she has the photographs? Our hands are tied.
她肯定喜歡你的措辭
She'd applaud your choice of words.
你看出這是怎麼回事了嗎
Do you see how this works?
那部攝像手機是她的免牢金牌
That camera- phone is her get out of jail free card.
你們得放過她  像對待皇室那樣對她  麥考夫
You have to leave her alone. Treat her like royalty, Mycroft.
可別像她對待皇室那樣對她
Though not the way she treats royalty.
那是什麼
What was that?
短信
Text.
可那聲音是什麼
But what was that noise?
你知道還有其他人在盯著她嗎  麥考夫
Did you know there were other people after her too, Mycroft,
早上好
福爾摩斯先生
你派我和約翰去之前就知道嗎
before you sent John and I in there?
好像是中情局的職業殺手
CIA trained killers, I think.
- 他們真不賴  - 是啊  多謝了  麥考夫
- Excellent gangs. - Yeah, thanks for that, Mycroft.
真不知羞
It's a disgrace,
把你弟弟派去那種龍潭虎穴
sending your little brother into danger like that.
你終究只有家人能依靠  麥考夫·福爾摩斯
Family is all we have in the end, Mycroft Holmes!
- 閉嘴吧  赫德森太太  - 麥考夫
- Oh, shut up, Mrs Hudson! - Mycroft!!
抱歉
Apologies.
- 謝謝  - 不過你確實該閉嘴了
- Thank you. - Though do in fact shut up.
這聲音不太好吧
Oh, it's a bit rude, that noise, isn't it?
感覺好些了嗎
你做不了什麼
There's nothing you can do
她也不會做什麼  至少依我看是如此
and nothing she will do, as far as I can see.
我可以給她設置最高監控級別
I can put maximum surveillance on her.
何必  你盯著推特就能跟蹤她的行程
Why bother? You can follow her on Twitter.
我想她的用戶名是"登頂女王"
I believe her user name is The Whip Hand.
是啊  真有趣
Yes. Most amusing.
失陪  喂
Excuse me. Hello?
你的手機為什麼會發出那種聲音
Why does your phone make that noise?
什麼聲音
What noise?
就是它剛剛發出的那種聲音
That noise, the one it just made.
那是短信的鈴音  意味著我收到短信了
It's a text alert, means I've got a text.
你的短信一般不會叫床
Your texts don't usually make that noise.
有人拿了我的手機  顯然開了個玩笑
Well, somebody got hold of the phone and apparently as a joke,
把短信鈴音個性化了
personalised their text alert noise.
那麼說你每次收到短信就會...
Hmm, so every time they text you...
看來如此
It would seem so.
你能把手機聲音關掉嗎  要是我那個年代...
Could you turn that phone down a bit? At my time of life it's...
既然你沒問起
我也很好
我在想誰會拿到你的手機
See I'm wondering who could have got hold of your phone.
手機是在你的大衣裏  對不對
It would've been in your coat, wouldn't it?
我不打擾你推理了
I'll leave you to your deductions.
要知道  我可不傻
I'm not stupid, you know.
你怎麼得出的這個結論
Where do you get that idea?
施行邦德航空計劃  已經決定了
Bond Air is go, that's decided.
跟考文垂那邊核實一下
Check with the Coventry lot.
回頭再談
Talk later.
她還有什麼
What else does she have?
艾琳·阿德勒  美國人不會為了幾張敏感照片
Irene Adler. The Americans wouldn't be interested in her
而對她感興趣
for a couple of compromising photographs.
她還有東西
There's more.
有很多
Much more.
有大事要發生了吧
Something big's coming, isn't it?
艾琳·阿德勒已經與你無關了
Irene Adler is no longer any concern of yours.
從現在起  你不要再插手此事
From now on, you will stay out of this.
- 是嗎  - 是的  夏洛克
- Oh, will I? - Yes, Sherlock.
正是如此
You will.
可以的話  恕我失陪
Now if you'll excuse me,
我得去向我多年的老朋友負荊請罪
I have a long and arduous apology to make to a very old friend.
記得代我向她問好
Do give her my love.
拉得太好了  夏洛克  太動聽了
Lovely, Sherlock. That was lovely.
- 餘音繞樑啊  - 對  太棒了
- Hmm, marvellous. - Yes, very good.
要是戴上聖誕鹿角就更完美了
I wish you could have worn the antlers.
赫德森太太  有些事總要留點想像才完美
Some things are best left to the imagination, Mrs Hudson.
赫德森太太
Mrs Hudson?
- 不用了  謝了  莎拉  - 別理他  他老記錯人名
- No thank you, Sarah. - Er, no, no, he's not good with names.
等等  我能記起來
No, I can get this.
莎拉是那個醫生  之後換了一臉痘痘的妹子
Sarah was the doctor, then there was the one with the spots,
再之後是一身香味的那個
then the one with the nose and then,
那個悶蛋老師之後是誰來著
who was after the boring teacher?
- 沒了  - 你是珍妮特  稍微排除下就出來了
- Nobody. - Jeanette! Ah, process of elimination.
天啊
Oh, dear Lord.
大家好  抱歉來晚了
Hello, everyone. Sorry, hello.
門上寫著說直接上來就行了
It said on the door to just come up.
- 茉莉  你好  - 茉莉  你好
- Hello, Molly. - Hello, Molly!
每來一個  就打一次招呼  好一個禮儀之邦
Everybody saying hello to each other, how wonderful!
讓我幫你...我的天啊
Let me, er... Holy Mary!
那我們現在要喝聖誕特飲了嗎
So we're having Christmas drinkies then?
顯然  你要喝  沒人攔你
No stopping them, apparently.
一年裏頭只有今天
It's the one day of the year
這些小鬼會好好地陪陪我
where the boys have to be nice to me,
所以也算值了
so it's almost worth it.
- 約翰  - 啥
- John? - Hmm?
你的博客還是只有1895次點擊
The counter on your blog still says 1895.
怎麼會  讓人聖誕節都沒心思過
Oh, no, Christmas is cancelled.
你竟然放了我戴帽子的那張照片
And you've got a photograph of me wearing that hat!
- 大家都愛這張  - 才怪  說誰呢
- People like it. - No, they don't. What people?
- 髖關節怎樣了  - 糟透了  謝謝關心
- How's the hip? - Oh, it's atrocious, but thanks for asking.
我見過更糟的  不過之後給我解剖了
I've seen much worse, but then I do post- mortems.
- 瞧我說的  抱歉  - 別說笑話  茉莉
- Oh, God, sorry. - Don't make jokes, Molly.
- 知道  抱歉  - 給你
- No, sorry. - Here you are.
謝謝  沒想到你也在
Thank you. I wasn't expecting to see you.
我以為你會在多塞特郡過聖誕
I thought you were in Dorset for Christmas?
今天一大早
The first thing in the morning,
我就和太太重歸於好了
me and the wife, back together, sorted.
瞎說  她跟一位體育老師上床了
No, she's sleeping with a PE teacher.
- 約翰  我聽說你要去你姐姐家吧  - 對
- And John, I hear you're off to your sister's? Is that right? - Yeah.
夏洛克抱怨過  錯  是說過
Sherlock was complaining. Saying.
有史以來她頭一回洗心革面  決定戒酒
First time ever, she's cleaned up her act, off the booze.
- 才怪  - 閉嘴  夏洛克
- Nope. - Shut up, Sherlock!
看來你找了個新男友  茉莉
I see you've got a new boyfriend, Molly.
- 你對他很認真啊  - 你說什麼
- You're serious about him. - Sorry, what?
- 你準備今晚見他  送他禮物  - 消停一天行嗎
- You're seeing him tonight, giving him a gift. - Take a day off.
- 住口  喝你的酒  - 你們別掃興
- Shut up. Have a drink. - Oh, come on.
你們肯定也看到袋子最上面那份禮物了
Surely you all see the present on the top of the bag.
包裝精美  還繫著蝴蝶結  其餘的包裝馬虎
Perfectly wrapped with a bow. The others are slapdash.
絕對是給特別的人
It's for someone special.
紅色包裝紙和口紅顏色一致
The shade of red echoes her lipstick,
也許是無意挑的
either an unconscious association,
也許是有意用它暗示對方
or one she's deliberately trying to encourage.
不管怎樣  霍普小姐墜入愛河了
Either way, Miss Hooper has love on her mind.
顯然她非常在乎他
That she's serious about him
從她送給他的禮物可見一斑
is clear from the fact she's giving him a gift at all.
顯然這表明她對這段關係渴望已久
That suggests long- time hopes asolutely for long.
從她的妝容和打扮
That she's seeing him tonight
可見她今晚一定會去見他
is evident from her make- up and what she is wearing.
顯然是想彌補自己嘴唇和胸部的不豐滿
Obviously trying to compensate for the size of her mouth and breasts.
致最親愛的夏洛克
茉莉敬上
你總是這樣出口傷人
You always say such horrible things.
每次都是  一而再  再而三
Every time. Always. Always.
對不起  原諒我
I am sorry. Forgive me.
聖誕快樂  茉莉·霍普
Merry Christmas, Molly Hooper.
別誤會  那不是我...
Oh, no! That wasn't, I didn't...
- 不是你  是我  - 我的天啊  真的假的
- No, it was me. - My God, really?
- 什麼  - 是我的手機
- What? - My phone.
- 第57條  - 你說什麼
- Fifty seven? - Sorry, what?
據我所知  那人已經發了57條短信了
Fifty seven of those texts, the ones I've heard.
看壁爐架
原來你一直有在數啊
Thrilling that you've been counting.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
夏洛克  怎麼了
What's up, Sherlock?
- 我說了  失陪一下  - 你就不回復一下嗎
- I said excuse me. - Do you ever reply?
哇  千年一遇呀
Oh, dear Lord,
該不會是打來祝我聖誕快樂的吧
we're not going to have Christmas phone calls now, are we?
難道我們國家頒布新政策了嗎
Have they passed a new law?
我想你們今晚就得去找艾琳·阿德勒
I think you're going to find Irene Adler tonight.
我們早就掌握她的行蹤了
We already know where she is.
雖然你好意提點  可惜這都跟你沒關繫了
As you were kind enough to point out, it hardly matters.
不  我意思是  你得去找她的屍體
No, I mean you're going to find her dead.
- 你還好吧  - 很好
- You OK? - Yes.
聖巴塞洛繆醫院
只有這具屍體符合描述
The only one who fitted the description.
於是把她轉來這邊  你的第二個家
Had her brought here, your home from home.
茉莉  你沒必要也過來
You didn't need to come in, Molly.
沒關係  大家都忙著過...聖誕
It's OK, everyone else is busy with... Christmas.
她有點毀容了
The face is a bit sort of bashed- up,
可能有點難以辨認
so it might be a bit difficult.
- 是她本人吧  - 給我看看身體
- That's her, isn't it? - Show me the rest of her.
是她沒錯
That's her.
謝謝  霍普小姐
Thank you, Miss Hooper.
她是誰
Who is she?
夏洛克為什麼光憑身體就認出了她
How did Sherlock recognise her from... not her face?
- 只此一根  - 為什麼
- Just the one. - Why?
聖誕快樂嘛
Merry Christmas.
室內抽煙  不是違反了某條...
Smoking indoors, isn't there one of those...
某條法律嗎
one of those law things?
這裏是停屍房
We're in a morgue.
抽煙也害不了幾個人
There's only so much damage you can do.
你怎麼知道她死了
How did you know she was dead?
她有一樣東西
She had an item in her possession,
她說過下半輩子都靠它了
one she said her life depended on.
- 如今卻拱手相讓  - 這樣東西在哪
- She chose to give it up. - Where is this item now?
你看看他們
Look at them.
投入這麼深的感情
They all care so much.
你有沒有想過咱倆也許有毛病
Do you ever wonder if there's something wrong with us?
生命都會終結  徒留一顆破碎的心
All lives end, all hearts are broken.
愛毫無用處  夏洛克
Caring is not an advantage, Sherlock.
這是低焦油香煙
This is low tar.
你都不怎麼瞭解她
Well, you barely knew her.
麥考夫  聖誕快樂
Merry Christmas, Mycroft.
新年快樂
And a happy new year.
他走了  你有沒有什麼發現
He's on his way. Have you found anything?
- 沒有  他有抽煙嗎  - 有
- No. Did he take the cigarette? - Yes.
我擦
Shit!
- 他還有十分鐘就到  - 臥室裏沒有發現
- He's coming, ten minutes. - There's nothing in the bedroom.
看來他沒藏煙  有可疑的地方我們都翻過了
It looks like he's clean, we've tried all the usual places.
你確定今晚會有危險嗎
Are you sure tonight's a danger night?
不確定  不過我向來如此
No, but then I never am.
約翰  你一定要陪著他
You have to stay with him, John.
我今晚有別的事
I've got plans.
推了
No.
麥考夫
Mycroft?
真是非常抱歉
I am really sorry.
- 我那些朋友完全看錯你了  - 咦
- You know my friends are so wrong about you. - Hmm?
你是個很棒的男朋友
You're a great boyfriend.
嗯  那就好
OK, that's good.
我一向覺得自己不錯
I always thought I was great.
所以說夏洛克·福爾摩斯太幸運了
Sherlock Holmes is a very lucky man.
珍妮特  別這樣
Oh, Jeanette, please.
我是說真的  太感人了
No, I mean it. It's heart- warming.
你願意為他做任何事
You'll do anything for him.
而他甚至搞混你的女朋友
And he can't even tell your girlfriends apart!
我也願意為你做任何事
I'll do anything for you,
你儘管開口  我一定做到  告訴我
just tell me what it is I'm not doing. Tell me!
我不想和夏洛克·福爾摩斯搶男朋友
Don't make me compete with Sherlock Holmes!
我可以幫你遛狗
I'll walk your dog for you.
我說到做到  我會幫你遛狗
There, I've said it, I'll even walk your dog.
- 我根本沒養狗  - 哦對  那是前任女友
- I don't have a dog! - No, because that was the last one.
- 抱歉  - 真是難以置信
- OK. - Jesus!
- 再聯繫  - 免了
- I'll call you. - No!
好吧
Ok.
看來你倆真的沒戲了吧
That really wasn't very good, was it?
回來了呀
Oh, hi.
你沒事吧
You OK?
希望你這回沒搞亂我的股票指數研究
I hope you didn't mess up my stock index this time!
曲子很美  夏洛克  以前沒聽你拉過
Lovely tune, Sherlock, haven't heard that one before.
在作曲嗎
Composing?
有助於思考
Helps me to think.
你在想些什麼呢
What are you thinking about?
你博客上的點擊還是只有1895次
The count on your blog is still stuck at 1895.
對  出故障了  似乎修不好
Yes. Faulty, can't seem to fix it.
是出故障  還是說博客被黑了  這個數字別有用意
Faulty, or you've been hacked and it's a message.
手機已鎖
密碼：
■
密碼錯誤
還有三次機會
是出故障了
Just faulty.
好的
Right.
好了
我要出去一會兒
Well, I'm going out for a bit.
那個  他有沒有過什麼女朋友
Listen, has he ever had any kind of girlfriend,
男朋友或走得近的人
boyfriend, a relationship, ever?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我們怎麼會不知道
How can we not know?
他可是夏洛克啊
He's Sherlock.
聰明古怪如他  誰能看透他的想法
How will we ever know what goes on in that funny old head?
說的也是  回見
Right. See you.
- 約翰  - 在  你好
- John? - Yeah? Hello?
- 你好  - 今晚打算怎麼過新年
- Hello. - So, any plans for new year tonight?
呃  沒什麼打算
Um, er... nothing fixed.
沒什麼非做不可的事
Nothing I couldn't heartlessly abandon.
- 你有什麼提議  - 有一個
- You have any ideas? - One.
其實  麥考夫只要給我個電話
You know, Mycroft could just phone me,
他就不能別每次都搞得這麼神經兮兮
if he didn't have this bloody stupid power complex.
我們就不能找間咖啡廳聊嗎
Couldn't we just go to a cafe?
夏洛克也不是一直跟著我
Sherlock doesn't follow me everywhere.
請往那邊走
Through there.
他馬上就到
He's on his way.
你說對了  他以為是麥考夫找他
You were right, he thinks it's Mycroft.
他在譜一首苦情曲
He's writing sad music.
不吃東西  幾乎不說話
Doesn't eat, barely talks,
偶爾給電視裏的節目糾下錯
only to correct the television.
依我看  他是真傷心了  但他可是夏洛克
I'd say he was heart- broken, but, er, well he's Sherlock.
反正傷人心的事他也沒少干
He does all that anyway.
你好  華生醫生
Hello, Dr Watson.
告訴他你還活著
Tell him you're alive.
那他不會放過我
He'd come after me.
如果你不告訴他  我也不會放過你
I'll come after you if you don't.
無庸置疑
Hmm, I believe you.
你的屍體在停屍台上
You were dead on a slab.
那絕對是你
It was definitely you.
DNA測試結果跟你們手上的資料一致
DNA tests are only as good as the records you keep.
- 那你肯定認識管資料的人  - 我知道他的癖好
- And I bet you know the record keeper. - I know what he likes.
而我則需要人間蒸發
And I needed to disappear.
那為什麼還來找我  而我還不想見你
Then how come I can see you and I don't even want to?
聽著  我犯了個錯誤
Look, I made a mistake,
我寄了樣東西給夏洛克保管  現在我得要回來
I sent something to Sherlock for safekeeping, now I need it back.
- 所以想請你幫忙  - 不行
- So I need your help. - No.
我是為了他的安全著想
It's for his own safety.
我這麼做也是  跟他說你還活著
So is this. Tell him you're alive.
- 我做不到  - 行  那我來說
- I can't. - Fine, I'll tell him
還有  我不會幫你
and I still won't help you.
我能說什麼呢
What do I say?
那你平常都說什麼了  你給他發了許多短信
What do you normally say?! You've texted him a lot!
- 只是聊聊罷了  - 你跟他能有什麼可聊
- Just the usual stuff. - There is no usual in this case.
早上好  我喜歡你那頂滑稽的帽子
"Good morning. I like your funny hat.
我今晚不高興  一起吃晚飯吧
"I'm sad tonight, let's have dinner.
你在《繩之於法》裏的樣子真性感  一起吃晚飯吧
"Hmm, you look sexy on Crimewatch, let's have dinner.
《繩之於法》是英國廣播公司一檔電視節目
我不餓
"I'm not hungry.
一起吃晚飯吧
"Let's have dinner".
- 你跟夏洛克·福爾摩斯調情  - 單方面  他從沒回過
- You flirted with Sherlock Holmes? - At him. He never replies.
不可能  夏洛克每條短信都回
No, Sherlock always replies to everything.
人稱"妙語連珠大師"
He's Mr Punchline.
他就是憋著一口氣不死都要說贏對方
He will outlive God trying to have the last word.
所以對他而言我很特別嗎
Does that make me special?
- 我不知道  也許是的  - 你吃醋了
- I don't know, maybe. - Are you jealous?
- 我們又不是一對  - 你們就是
- We're not a couple. - Yes, you are.
我發了  我沒死
There, "I'm not dead.
我們一起吃飯吧
"Let's have dinner".
其實又有誰真正瞭解夏洛克·福爾摩斯
Who the hell knows about Sherlock Holmes?
以免這世上仍有人在乎  我還是聲明一下
But for the record, if anyone out there still cares,
我可不是同性戀
I'm not actually gay.
可我是  看看咱們倆
Well, I am. Look at us both.
不會是我想的那樣吧  你覺得呢
I don't think so, do you?
住手
Stop it!
夏洛克
Sherlock!
- 夏洛克  - 赫德森太太  別哭哭啼啼了
- Oh, Sherlock, Sherlock... - Don't snivel, Mrs Hudson,
再哭  他也不會心軟收起槍
it'll do nothing to impede the flight of a bullet.
否則那該是個多麼柔情的世界啊
What a tender world that would be.
救救我  夏洛克
Oh, please, Sherlock...
我想你手上有我們想要的東西  福爾摩斯先生
I believe that you have something that we want, Mr Holmes.
那你為什麼不問我要
Then why don't you ask for it?
我問過這位了  不過她看來啥都不曉得
Oh, I've been asking this one, she doesn't seem to know anything.
但你心裏清楚我要什麼  對吧  福爾摩斯先生
But you know what I'm asking for, don't you, Mr Holmes?
頸動脈
顱骨
眼睛
動脈
肋骨
肺部
我當然清楚
I believe I do.
求你救救我
Please, help.
先把你的手下打發走
First get rid of your boys.
- 為什麼  - 我不喜歡以一敵三
- Why? - I dislike being outnumbered,
不然這間屋子裏的蠢貨就太多了
it makes for too much stupid in the room.
- 你們兩個回車裏  - 然後開車走人
- You two, go to the car. - Then get into the car and drive away.
別想騙我  你知道我是誰  這可沒用
Don't try to trick me, you know who I am, it doesn't work.
然後別再用槍指著我
Next, you can stop pointing that gun at me.
好讓你用槍指著我嗎
So you can point a gun at me?
我沒槍
I'm unarmed.
- 能讓我搜下嗎  - 快來搜
- Mind if I check? - Oh, I insist.
白癡
Moron.
- 謝謝  - 你沒事了
- Oh, thank you. - You're all right now, you're all right.
犯罪現場
務必打擾
怎麼了
What's going on?
臥槽  這究竟是怎麼了
Jeez, what the hell is happening?
赫德森太太被個美國人打了
Mrs Hudson has been attacked by an American,
我是在聲張正義
I'm restoring balance to the universe.
赫德森太太  老天啊  你沒事吧
Mrs Hudson, my God, are you all right?
他們對你做了什麼
Jesus, what have they done to you?
我真是太蠢了
Oh, I'm just being so silly.
把她帶到樓下去  照看好她
Take her downstairs and look after her.
沒事了  我來給你看看
It's all right, I'll have a look at that.
我沒事
I'm fine, I'm fine.
你到底要不要告訴我是怎麼回事
Are you going to tell me what's going on?
當然了  快去
I expect so, now go.
雷斯垂德
Lestrade?
有人非法闖入我們在貝克街的公寓
We've had a break- in at Baker Street.
把你手下最不討人厭的警官派來  再叫輛救護車
Send your least irritating officers and an ambulance.
不不不  我們沒事
Oh, no, no, no, we're fine.
是那個闖入者  他把自己弄傷了
No, it's the burglar, he's got himself rather badly injured.
斷了幾根肋骨  腦震盪
Oh, a few broken ribs, fractured skull,
還可能傷了肺
suspected punctured lung...
他從窗子摔下去了
He fell out of a window.
真疼
Oh, it stings.
摔在了我的垃圾桶上
Oh, that was right on my bins.
他到底摔下來了幾次
And exactly how many times did he fall out the window?
我記不清了  警長大人
It's all a bit of a blur, Detective Inspector.
沒數
I lost count.
她今晚得睡在樓上我們房間
She'll have to sleep upstairs in our flat tonight,
我們得照顧她
we need to look after her.
- 不  - 她沒事
- No... - She's fine. -
不  她有事  看看她
No, she's not, look at her.
她得搬離貝克街幾天
She's got to take some time away from Baker Street.
她可以去她姐姐家住  這是醫囑
She can stay with her sister, doctor's orders.
- 別傻了  - 老天爺  她受驚了
- Don't be absurd. - She's in shock, for God's sake,
都是因為那天煞的攝像手機  手機到底在哪啊
and all over some stupid camera- phone - where is it anyway?
我知道的最安全的地方
Safest place I know.
你把手機放在你第二好的
You left it in the pocket
睡衣袍子口袋裏了  你個呆子
of your second best dressing gown, you clot!
他們以為我被嚇哭的時候  我想辦法拿了出來
I managed to sneak it out when they thought I was having a cry.
謝謝
Thank you.
你真丟臉  約翰·華生
Shame on you, John Watson.
- 我咋丟臉了  - 赫德森太太怎麼能離開貝克街
- Shame on me? - Mrs Hudson leave Baker Street?
不然英國可要淪陷了
England would fall.
手機現在又在哪
Where is it now?
沒人會找的地方
Where no- one will look.
不管那手機上有什麼  肯定不只是照片
Whatever's on that phone is more than just pictures.
沒錯
Yes, it is.
這麼說她還活著
So, she's alive then.
你對此感覺如何
How are we feeling about that?
新年快樂  約翰
Happy New Year, John.
你覺得你會再見到她嗎
Do you think you'll be seeing her again?
新年快樂
夏·福
- 那是手機嗎  - 是部攝像手機
- Is that a phone? - It's a camera- phone.
- 你在掃瞄手機嗎  - 是的
- And you're x- raying it? - Yes, I am.
- 那是誰的手機  - 一個女人的
- Whose phone is it? - A woman's.
是你女朋友嗎
Your girlfriend?
我掃瞄她的東西就代表她是我女友了嗎
She's my girlfriend because I'm x- raying her possessions?
- 我們都會做傻事  - 那是
- Well, we all do silly things! - Yes...
真的是這樣吧
..They do, don't they?
很傻
Very silly.
她把手機送到我公寓的地址
She sent this to my address.
手機已鎖
密碼：
■
- 她就是愛玩遊戲  - 是嗎
- She loves to play games. - She does?
B
密碼錯誤
還有兩次機會
夏洛克
Hey, Sherlock...
我們有了個客戶
We have a client.
啥  在你臥室裏嗎
What, in your bedroom?
那  誰在追殺你
So, who's after you?
- 想要殺我的人  - 是什麼人
- People who want to kill me. - Who's that?
殺手唄
Killers.
你說得再具體一點也無妨
It would help if you were a tiny bit more specific.
這麼說你假造了你的死
So you faked your own death
就是為了擺脫他們嗎  - 成功了一陣子
to get ahead of them? - It worked for a while.
但接著你告訴了約翰  也就是告訴了我
Except you let John know you're alive, therefore me.
我知道你會替我保密
I knew you'd keep my secret.
但你不行
You couldn't.
但你確實沒說出去吧
But you did, didn't you?
我的攝像手機呢
Where's my camera- phone?
不在這
It's not here.
我們又不蠢
We're not stupid.
你們拿它做了什麼
What have you done with it?
如果他們認為手機在你手上  肯定會監視你
If they've guessed you got it, they'll be watching you.
那他們會以為我幾個月前
Then they'll know I took a safety deposit box
在斯特蘭德找了個保險儲存箱
at a bank on the Strand a few months ago.
我需要那部手機
I need it.
我們不能就這麼過去拿吧
Well, we can't just go and get it, can we?
茉莉·霍普  她能把手機拿到巴茨醫院
Molly Hooper, she could collect it, take it to Barts.
再讓某個替你跑腿的流浪漢
Then one of your homeless
帶到樓下的咖啡廳裏
network could bring it here, leave it in the cafe,
讓咖啡廳裏的招待再把手機拿上來
one of the boys downstairs could bring it up the back.
好極了  約翰  計劃得好  能想到的都想到了
Very good, John, excellent plan, full of intelligent precautions.
謝謝  所以我這就去打電話給...
Thank you. So, why don't I phone...
這裏面你都藏了什麼
So, what do you keep on here?
我是說大致上
In general, I mean?
照片  情報  所有我覺得有用的東西
Pictures, information, anything I might find useful.
- 為了敲詐嗎  - 是為了保護自己
- For blackmail? - For protection.
我一個人闖天下  難免有不得當的地方
I make my way in the world, I misbehave.
我得保證在我需要的時候
I like to know people will
別人能為我提供幫助
be on my side exactly when I need them to be.
那你是怎麼搞來的這些情報
So how do you acquire this information?
我也說了  我的行為不得當
I told you - I misbehave.
但你得到了比能保護自己
But you've acquired something more
- 更危險的情報  你知道是什麼嗎  - 知道
- danger than protection. Do you know what it is? - Yes...
但我搞不懂
..But I don't understand it.
我想也是  讓我看看
I assumed. Show me.
密碼
The passcode.
密碼沒用
It's not working.
當然  因為這只是我做的復製品
No, because it's a duplicate I had made
好讓我知道你輸入了什麼密碼  是1058
into which you just entered the numbers 1058.
我本以為你會選擇
I assumed you'd choose something
更有意義的密碼  不過還是謝了
more specific than that, but thanks, anyway.
手機已鎖
密碼：
■
手機已鎖
密碼：
密碼錯誤
還有一次機會
我也說過那部手機是我的生命
I told you that camera- phone was my life.
是不是真的我一摸就知道
I know when it's in my hand.
你真厲害
Oh, you're rather good.
你也不賴
You're not so bad.
哈米什
Hamish.
約翰·哈米什·華生不錯  作為孩子名字的話
John Hamish Watson, just if you were looking for baby names.
有個男人  一個國防部的官員  我知道他的癖好
There was a man, an MOD official and I knew what he liked.
他就是喜歡炫耀
One of the things he liked was showing off.
他告訴我說  這封郵件可以拯救世界
He told me this email was going to save the world.
他不知道我拍了下來
He didn't know it but I photographed it.
他當時有點脫不開身
He was a bit tied up at the time.
屏幕上看有點小  你能看清楚嗎
It's a bit small on that screen, can you read it?
007確認位置
- 能  - 顯然是密碼
- Yes. - Code, obviously.
我讓英國最厲害的解碼專家看了看
I had one of the country's best cryptographers take a look,
他也被搞得一頭霧水
though he was mostly upside down, as I recall.
解不開
Couldn't figure it out.
你有辦法嗎  福爾摩斯先生
What can you do, Mr Holmes?
來吧  露一手給姑娘看看
Go on, impress a girl.
還有一點沒想明白
There's a margin for error,
但我肯定是架波音747
but I'm pretty sure there's a 747
明天六點半將於西斯羅機場起飛  飛往巴爾的摩
leaving Heathrow tomorrow at 6.30 for Baltimore.
顯然這條信息能拯救世界  但我不確定怎麼個救法
Apparently it's going to save the world, I'm not sure how,
但等我一會  我才想了八秒鐘
but give me a moment, I've only been on the case eight seconds.
得了  這不是密碼  是飛機上的座位
Oh, come on, it's not code, these are seats on a jet.
看  沒有字母I  因為會和數字1搞混
Look, no 'I' because it can be mistaken for one.
沒有K以後的字母  因為飛機就這麼寬
No letters past 'K' - the width of the plane is the limit.
數字總是不按順序排列
The numbers always appear not in sequence,
但字母則幾乎沒有亂過順序
but the letters have little runs of sequence all over the place.
家人和夫妻都坐在一起
Families and couples sitting together.
只有巨型噴氣式飛機的座椅才會排到K
Only a Jumbo's wide enough for a letter 'K'
還有55排  所以機頂上還有一層
or rows past 55, so there's always an upstairs.
有13排說明不是那些迷信的航空公司
A row 13 eliminates superstitious airlines.
航班號的組合規律  007  又能排除一些信息
The style of the flight number, '007', eliminates a few more.
考慮到最初的情報來源
Assuming a British point
可以推斷航班從英國起飛
of origin because of the original source,
加上迫在眉睫的危機  唯一符合所有條件
and assuming the crisis is imminent, the only flight that matches
並且在本周起飛的飛機
all the criteria and departs within the week is the
就是六點半從倫敦到巴爾的摩的飛機
6.30 to Baltimore tomorrow from Heathrow.
別急著要讚揚我
Please don't feel obliged to tell me that was amazing,
約翰已經這麼幹過了
John's expressed that in
他用光了所有表示讚揚的詞語
every possible variant available in English.
我真想在這個書桌上要了你
I would have you right here, on this desk,
要到你求饒  還是兩次
until you begged for mercy twice.
約翰  你能否查下航班表  看看我說得對不對
John, can you check those flight schedules, see if I'm right?
在查了
I'm on it, yeah.
我這輩子都沒求過繞
I've never begged for mercy in my life.
你這次要求饒  還是兩次
Twice.
嗯  你說得沒錯  007號航班
Yeah, you're right, flight double 'o' seven.
- 你說什麼  - 你說得沒錯
- What did you say? - You're right.
不  你之後說了什麼
No, what did you say after that?
007  007號航班
Double 'o' seven, flight double 'o' seven.
007  007
Double 'o' seven, double 'o' seven...
007有什麼含義
Something, double 'o' seven...
是什麼
What?
波音
明天
晚上
六點半
西斯羅
機場
波音 747 明天晚上 六點半 西斯羅 機場
007  是什麼
Double 'o' seven, double 'o' seven, what?
到底是什麼
What, something, what?!
施行邦德航空計劃
Bond Air is go.
噴氣式
飛機
向你
問好
親愛
的
福爾摩斯
先生
噴氣式飛機 向你 問好 親愛 的 福爾摩斯先生
噴氣式飛機  向你問好  親愛的福爾摩斯先生
施行邦德航空計劃  已經決定了
'Bond Air is go, that's decided.
跟考文垂那邊核實一下
'Check with the Coventry lot.'
- 考文垂  - 我從沒去過
- Coventry. - I've never been.
那裏怎麼樣
Is it nice?
約翰呢
Where's John?
他出去了  出去了幾小時了
He went out, a couple of hours ago.
我就是在和他說話
I was just talking to him.
他說了你會這樣
He said you do that.
考文垂和這又有什麼關係
What's Coventry got to do with anything?
這只是個說法  不知是真是假
It's a story, probably not true -
在二戰期間
in the Second World War,
盟軍知道考文垂會被德軍轟炸
the allies knew Coventry was going to get bombed,
因為他們破解了德軍的密碼機
because they'd broken the German code,
但他們不想讓德國知道他們破了密碼
but didn't want the Germans to know that they've broken the code.
所以他們就任其被轟炸了
so they let it happen anyway.
你有和誰親密接觸過嗎
Have you ever had anyone?
你說什麼
I'm sorry?
我說的接觸可是下流含義哦
And when I say had, I'm being indelicate.
- 我不懂  - 那我婉轉點吧
- I don't understand. - I'll be delicate then.
- 一起吃晚飯吧  - 為什麼
- Let's have dinner. - Why?
- 你餓了吧  - 不餓  - 很好
- You might be hungry. - I'm not. - Good.
我為什麼想要吃晚飯
Why would I...want to have dinner...
既然我不餓
..If I wasn't hungry?
福爾摩斯先生  如果這是世界末日
Mr Holmes, if it was the end of the world,
如果這是毀滅前的最後一晚
if this was the very last night...
你會和我一起吃晚飯嗎
..Would you have dinner with me?
夏洛克
Sherlock?
太遲了
Too late.
這不是世界末日  而是赫德森太太
That's not the end of the world, that's Mrs Hudson.
夏洛克  有個男人來了
Sherlock, this man was at the door,
門鈴不會壞了吧
is the bell still not working?
他打壞了
He shot it.
你又是來帶走我的嗎
Have you come to take me away again?
- 是的  福爾摩斯先生  - 那我拒絕
- Yes, Mr Holmes. - Well, I decline.
我覺得你不會拒絕
I don't think you do.
飛機的座椅上會有一枚炸彈
There's going to be a bomb on a passenger jet.
英國人和美國人都知道這一點
The British and Americans know about it,
但為了不暴露他們的情報來源
but rather than expose their source
他們決定任其發生  飛機會爆炸
they're going to let it happen - the plane will blow up.
考文垂事件的重演
Coventry all over again.
時過境遷  爛事依然
The wheel turns, nothing is ever new.
你看上去好多了
Well, you're looking all better.
感覺怎麼樣
How you feeling?
比如想衝你腦袋來上一槍嗎  先生
Like putting a bullet in your brain, sir.
我要是這麼幹了  他們會賞我一枚獎章
They'd pin a medal on me if I did...
先生
..Sir.
考文垂難題
The Coventry conundrum.
你覺得我的解決方法如何
What do you think of my solution?
死者航班
The flight of the dead.
飛機在半空中爆炸  恐怖分子達到了目的
Plane blows up midair, mission accomplished for the terrorists,
傷亡數上百  但沒人死亡
hundreds of casualties, but nobody dies.
很乾淨吧  你覺得呢
Neat, don't you think?
其實你很早就接觸到事情的真相了
You've been stumbling around the fringes of this one for ages.
還是說你覺得太無聊  而忽略了其中的規律
Or were you too bored to notice the pattern?
爺爺去世時他們不讓我們去看他
They wouldn't let us see Granddad when he was dead.
她不是我姑姑  我分辨得出人的骨灰
She's not my real aunt - I know human ash.
我們之前和德國人有過類似的合作
We ran a similar project with the Germans a while back,
而其中一位乘客沒有趕上飛機
though I believe one of our passengers didn't make the flight.
就是你的那件案子的死者
But that's the deceased for you...
無論如何  太遲了
..late, in every sense of the word.
飛機要怎麼飛
How is the plane going to fly?
當然了  無人駕駛  老把戲了
Oh, of course, unmanned aircraft, hardly new.
它不會起飛
It doesn't fly.
永遠不會
It will never fly.
整個計劃都取消了
This entire project is cancelled.
恐怖組織得知了我們知道炸彈的事
The terrorist cells have been informed that we know about the bomb.
現在騙不了他們了
We can't fool them now.
我們輸得一敗塗地
We've lost everything.
一封郵件中的一小段話
One fragment of one email,
成年累月的計劃  結束了
and months and years of planning - finished.
- 你國防部的手下  - 老鼠屎壞了一鍋粥
- Your MOD man. - That's all it takes.
一個孤獨幼稚的男人  總想顯擺自己
One lonely, naive man, desperate to show off,
和一個聰明到讓他自以為很特別的女人
and a woman clever enough to make him feel special.
你們國防部選人時應該更謹慎點
You should screen your defence people more carefully.
我沒在說那個國防部的人
I'm not talking about the MOD man,
夏洛克  我說的是你
Sherlock, I'm talking about you!
身陷困境的少女
The damsel in distress.
到頭來  你的觀察力還這麼敏銳嗎
In the end, are you really so obvious?
因為這不是明擺著的嗎
Because this was textbook.
愛的承諾  失去的痛苦  挽回的快樂
The promise of love, the pain of loss, the joy of redemption.
然後再給他個謎題  看他盡情發揮
Then give him a puzzle and watch him dance.
別胡說了
Don't be absurd!
胡說
Absurd?
幫她破解那封郵件你用了多久
How quickly did you decipher that email for her?
一分鐘嗎
Was it the full minute?
還是你就這麼想表現一下
Or were you really eager to impress?
我看不到5秒鐘
I think it was less than five seconds.
是我讓你著了她的道
I drove you into her path.
抱歉  我真沒想到
I'm sorry, I didn't know.
福爾摩斯先生  看來我們得談談
Mr Holmes, I think we need to talk.
我也覺得  還有很多事我不太清楚
So do I, there are a number of aspects I'm still not clear on.
不是你  小阿福  沒你的事了
Not you, Junior, you're done now.
還有很多  非常多
There's more, loads more.
這手機裏存著秘密  照片
On this phone I've got secrets, pictures
還有能讓你一敗塗地的醜聞
and scandals that could topple your whole world.
你無法想像我能造成多大的破壞
You have no idea how much havoc I can cause
你也不知道如何阻止我
and exactly one way to stop me.
除非你想告訴你的上司
Unless you want to tell your masters
你最大的安全漏洞就是你弟弟
that your biggest security leak is your own little brother.
我們可以找人破解你的手機
We have people who can get into this.
我早就試過了
I tested that theory for you.
我給了夏洛克·福爾摩斯六個月時間
I let Sherlock Holmes try it for six months.
親愛的夏洛克
Sherlock, dear, tell him
告訴他你掃瞄我手機時發現了什麼
what you found when you x- rayed my camera phone.
手機殼下面裝了四個零件
There are four additional units wired inside the casing,
我猜是含酸物質或微型炸藥
I suspect containing acid or a small amount of explosive.
如果有人試圖打開手機殼  硬盤就會銷毀
Any attempt to open the casing will burn the hard drive.
是炸藥
Explosive.
更符合我性格
It's more me.
有些數據是可恢復的
Some data is always recoverable.
你可以試試
Take that risk.
解鎖需要密碼
You have a passcode to open this.
很遺憾地告訴你
I deeply regret to say,
我們可以把密碼逼問出來
we have people who can extract it from you.
- 夏洛克  - 有兩組密碼
- Sherlock? - There will be two passcodes -
一個可以解鎖  一個會燒掉驅動
one to open the phone, one to burn the drive.
就算威脅她  也不知道她給的是哪一個
Even under duress, you can't know which one she's giving you
- 而機會只有一次  - 他真是厲害
- and there would be no point in second attempt. - He's good, isn't he?
我真該好好調教他
I should have him on a leash.
值得一試
In fact, I might.
那我們就毀了它  誰也別想得到裏面的信息
We destroy this, then. No- one has the information.
行  好注意
Fine, good idea.
不過你要毀掉的這信息
Unless there are lives of British citizens
可是這關繫著英國人民的生死
depending on the information you burn.
- 是嘛  - 告訴你是為你好
- Are there? - Telling you would be playing fair.
我不想再玩遊戲了
I'm not playing any more.
這是我的要求
A list of my requests,
還要對我進行絕對安全的保護措施
find some ideas about my protection once they're granted.
要說這花不了國家多少錢
I'd say it wouldn't blow much of a hole in the wealth of a nation,
那是假的
but then I'd be lying.
你可能需要時間考慮一下
I imagine you'd like to sleep on it.
謝謝  沒錯
Thank you, yes.
真可惜
Too bad.
你可以去著手辦這件事了
Off you pop and talk to people.
你考慮得十分周道
You've been very...thorough.
我們的人能有你一半能耐就好了
I wish our lot were half as good as you.
並不是全靠我自己  有人幫我
I can't take all the credit, I had a bit of help.
金·莫裏亞蒂向你們問好
Jim Moriarty sends his love.
是  他就沒消停過
Yes, he's been in touch.
迫不及待想讓我盯上他
Seems desperate for my attention,
那我就滿足他
which I'm sure can be arranged.
信息一直在我手上  但我不知道怎麼辦
I had all this stuff and never knew what to do with it.
多謝這個犯罪顧問
Thank God for the consultant criminal.
給了我很多建議
Gave me a lot of advice
教我如何跟你們打交道
about how to play the Holmes boys.
知道他叫你們什麼嗎
Do you know what he calls you?
冰人
The Ice Man...
和處子
..and the Virgin.
他不要任何回報  我想他只是喜歡搗亂
Didn't even ask for anything, I think he just likes to cause trouble
我要的就是這種男人
now that's my kind of man.
所以成全了你
And here you are,
讓全國為之屈服的施虐女王
the dominatrix who brought a nation to its knees.
幹得漂亮
Nicely played.
不
No.
什麼
Sorry?
我說不
I said no.
差點成功  不過沒戲
Very, very close, but no.
你太入迷了
You got carried away.
但你的遊戲玩過了  你過於沉迷了
The game was too elaborate, you were enjoying yourself too much.
可沒有"過頭"這一說
There's no such thing as too much.
你可以享受追捕的興奮感
Oh, enjoying the thrill of the chase is fine.
渴望用這遊戲作為消遣  我完全贊同
Craving the distraction of the game, I sympathise entirely,
可你太感情用事
but sentiment?
感情用事是失敗者的生理缺陷
Sentiment is a chemical defect found in the losing side.
感情用事  你說什麼呢
Sentiment? What are you talking about?
你
You.
老天
Oh, dear God.
看看這個小可憐
Look at the poor man.
你不會真覺得我對你有興趣吧
You don't actually think I was interested in you?
為什麼
Why?
因為你是偉大的夏洛克·福爾摩斯
Because you're the great Sherlock Holmes,
戴著滑稽帽子的大偵探
the clever detective in the funny hat?
不
No.
因為我摸到了你的脈搏
Because I took your pulse.
脈搏加快
Elevated.
瞳孔放大
Your pupils dilated.
我猜約翰·華生覺得我不解風情
I imagine John Watson thinks love's a mystery to me,
但兩人碰出火花非常簡單  而且十分致命
but the chemistry is incredibly simple and very destructive.
我們初次見面時你說
When we first met, you told me that
偽裝是一幅自畫像  一點沒錯
disguise is always a self- portrait - how true of you.
保險櫃的密碼是你的三圍
the combination to your safe, your measurements -
但這個  這個就私人多了
but this, this is far more intimate,
這是你的心  而你不應該隨心而為
this is your heart and you should never let it rule your head.
如果你隨便選組數字做密碼
You could have chosen any random number
今天你就能順利從這裏離開
and walked out of here today with everything you work for.
但你就是忍不住  對吧
But you just couldn't resist it, could you?
我一直認為愛是個危險的不利因素
I've always assumed that love is a dangerous disadvantage.
感謝你最終又證明了這一點
Thank you for the final proof.
我所說的一切都是假的
Everything I said, it's not real.
我只是在玩遊戲而已
I was just playing the game.
我知道
I know.
而你輸了
And this is just losing.
手機已鎖
密碼：
S
■
H
E
■
R
[整句話雙關]
給你  老哥
There you are, brother,
菜單
文檔
圖片
秘密
聲音
希望裏面的內容足以彌補
hope the contents make up for any inconvenience
今晚我給你造成的任何麻煩
I may have caused you tonight.
- 肯定可以  - 你要是好心  就把她關起來
- I'm certain they will. - If you're feeling kind, lock her up,
放她走的話  沒了手機她肯定活不長
otherwise let her go and I doubt she'll survive long without her pretection.
- 你是要我求你嗎  - 對
- Are you expecting me to beg? - Yes.
求你
Please.
你說得對
You're right.
我肯定活不過半年
I won't even last six months.
晚飯的事情抱歉了
Sorry about dinner.
你不抽煙
You don't smoke.
我也從不來咖啡館
I also don't frequent cafes.
這是艾琳·阿德勒的檔案
This the file on Irene Adler?
永久封檔
Closed forever.
我正要去通知我弟弟
I am about to go and inform my brother -
或者你願意的話  由你去說
or, if you prefer, you are -
她在美國申請到了
that she somehow got herself
證人保護計劃
into a witness protection scheme in America.
新名字  新身份
New name, new identity.
她會健康地活著
She will survive and thrive...
但是他永遠見不到她了
..but he will never see her again.
他會在意麼
Why would he care?
最後是他摒棄了她
He despised her at the end.
提起她都不說名字  只是說"那個女人"
Won't even mention her by name, just 'The Woman'.
那是厭惡還是讚揚
Is that loathing or a salute?
獨一無二  唯一讓他在意的女人
One of a kind, the one woman who matters.
他不是那種人
He's not like that.
我覺得他不會有這種感覺
He doesn't feel things that way, I don't think.
我弟弟的大腦堪比科學家或哲學家
My brother has the brain of a scientist or a philosopher,
可他選擇當名偵探
yet he elects to be a detective.
關於他的內心  我們能推論多少
What might we deduce about his heart?
我不知道
I don't know.
我也不知道
Neither do I.
但他最初的願望是當一名海盜
But, initially, he wanted to be a pirate.
他應該可以接受
He'll be OK with this -
證人保護計劃  再也不能見面  他不會有事
witness protection, never seeing her again - he'll be fine.
我同意
I agree.
所以我決定這樣告訴他
That's why I decided to tell him that.
那事實是什麼
Instead of what?
她死了
She's dead.
兩個月前  她被卡拉奇的一個恐怖組織俘獲
She was captured by a terrorist cell in Karachi two months ago
被砍頭了
and beheaded.
確定是她本人嗎
It was definitely her?
她耍過一次詐
She's done this before.
這次我保證萬無一失
I was thorough this time.
想騙我得夏洛克·福爾摩斯親自出馬
It would take Sherlock Holmes to fool me,
可我覺得他並不在場  對吧
and I don't think he was on hand, do you?
所以
So...
我們怎麼對夏洛克說
what shall we tell Sherlock?
看來你有消息要告訴我
Clearly you've got news.
如果是利茲三連環殺人案的話  兇手是園丁
If it's about the Leeds triple murder, it was the gardener.
- 就沒人注意到耳環麼  - 好啊
- Nobody notice the earring? - Hi.
不  是關於艾琳·阿德勒的事
Er no, it's, um...it's about Irene Adler.
怎麼了
Well?
出事了嗎  她回來了
Something happened? Has she come back?
沒  她...
No, she's...
我在樓下遇到麥考夫了  他要去接個電話
I just bumped into Mycroft downstairs, he had to take a call.
她回倫敦了嗎
Is she back in London?
沒
No...
她...
She's, er...
- 她在美國  - 美國
- She's in America. - America?
看來她申請到了證人保護計劃
Got herself on a witness protection scheme, apparently.
不知道她怎麼辦到  但是...
Don't know how she swung it, but...
你懂的
well, you know.
- 懂什麼  - 你不能再見她了
- I know what? - You won't be able to see her again.
- 我為什麼想再見她  - 我也沒這麼說
- Why would I want to see her again? - Didn't say you did.
- 這是她的檔案嗎  - 是
- Is that her file? - Yes,
我正要拿去還給麥考夫
I was going to take it back to Mycroft.
- 你想要...  - 不要
- Do you want to... - No.
那個  其實...
Listen, actually...
把她的手機給我
But I will have the camera- phone though.
- 裏面沒東西了  都被刪掉了  - 我知道
- There's nothing on it anymore, it's been stripped... - I know, but I...
但我還是想要
..I'll still have it.
我得把它還給麥考夫  你不能留著
I've got to give this back to Mycroft, you can't keep it.
夏洛克  我得把它還給麥考夫
Sherlock, I have to give this to Mycroft,
這是政府財產了
it's the government's now...
拜託了
Please.
謝謝
Thank you.
- 我得把東西還回去了  - 好
- Well, I'd better take this back. - Yes.
在那之後  她有再給你發過短信嗎
Did she ever text you again, after all that?
幾個月前有一次
Once, a few months ago.
說了什麼
What did she say?
再見  福爾摩斯先生
"Goodbye, Mr Holmes."
發信人  那個女人:
我不餓  一起吃晚飯吧
在賓館好無聊  你過來吧
一起吃晚飯
約翰的博客好好笑
我看他比我更喜歡你
一起吃晚飯吧
我房間能看到塔橋和月亮
推理出我在哪
過來找我
今天我在街上看見你了
你沒看見我
你知道那帽子很適合你吧
我的天呀  一起吃晚飯吧
我喜歡你那頂滑稽的帽子
我在埃及  和個白癡說話
正要上飛機
一起吃晚飯吧
你在電視上真性感
就算是你也得吃飯  一起吃晚飯吧
快看BBC1台  太搞笑了
我想給你寄個聖誕禮物
壁爐台
我沒死  一起吃晚飯吧
回復:
新年快樂
再見  福爾摩斯先生
發送
聽我口令
When I say run...
快跑
..run!
那個女人
The woman.
特別的女人
新福爾摩斯 第2季 第1集
Sherlock S02E01 720p hdtv x264
YYeTs人人影視